export const questions = [
    {
        question: "<h1>What is period poverty?</h1>",
        answers: [
            "The lack of a normal menstrual cycle",
            "Inadequate access to menstrual products and education"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        info: "Period poverty is the inadequate access to menstrual products and education. Much of the issue goes unseen and unspoken about because of the stigma that still surrounds menstruation."
    },
    {
        question: "<h1>What is the 'Pink Tax'?</h1>",
        answers: [
            "A tampon brand",
            "A tax placed on menstrual products",
            "A tax placed on feminine products",
            "the tendency for 'feminine' products to be more expensive"
        ],
        correct: 3,
        info: "The 'Pink Tax' is the tendency for 'feminine' products to be more expensive. These products include razors, shampoo, haircuts, clothes, dry cleaning."
    },
    {
        question: "<h1>Does period poverty exist in the US?</h1>",
        answers: [
            "Yes",
            "No, period poverty only exists in third-world countries."
        ],
        correct: 0,
        info: "Period poverty is a global issue. Currently, 35 states impose 'tampon tax' on menstrual products. More women than men live in poverty in the US, but menstruation products cannot be purchased with food stamps or health insurance."
    },
    {
        question: "<h1>What is amenorrhea?</h1>",
        answers: [
            "extremely light menstrual periods",
            "the absence of monthly menstrual periods",
            "extremely heavy menstrual periods"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        info: "Amenorrhea is the absence of monthly menstrual periods. It occurs when a woman fails to menstruate for 3 to 6 months."
    },
    {
        question: "<h1>Globally, how many people lack access to basic sanitation services?</h1>",
        answers: [
            "757 million",
            "2.3 billion",
            "1.8 billion"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        info: "Globally, 2.3 billion people lack access to basic sanitation services."
    },
    {
        question: "<h1>Why is period poverty an issue?</h1>",
        answers: [
            "menstrual stigma",
            "low income",
            "loss of affordable supply",
            "all of the above"
        ],
        correct: 3,
        info: "There are many causes of period poverty that are deeply entrenched in our society. These include menstrual stigma, low income or loss of income, loss of affordable supply (like during the pandemic)."
    },
    {
        question: "<h1>In the UK, one in _ girls have been unable to afford sanitary wear.</h1>",
        answers: [
            "five",
            "ten",
            "fifteen"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        info: "In the UK, one in ten girls have been unable to afford sanitary wear."
    },
    {
        question: `<h1>What are the causes of amenorrhea?</h1>
        i. birth control<br>
        ii. stress <br>
        iii. poor nutrition <br>
        iv. pregnancy <br>
        v. excessive exercise 
        `,
        answers: [
            "I and IV",
            "II, II, and V",
            "I, II, II, IV, V",
            "all except I" 
        ],
        correct: 2,
        info: "Amenorrhea can be caused by birth control, stress, poor nutrition, pregnancy, or excessive exercise."
    },
    {
        question: "<h1>When proper products are not available, women resort to using socks, dishrags, and newspapers. True or false?</h1>",
        answers: [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        correct: 0,
        info: "When proper menstrual products are not available, women are forced to resort to using alternatives such as socks, dishrags, and newspapers."
    },
    {
        question: `<h1>Which are possible reasons that girls miss school due to their periods?</h1>
        i. they don't have menstrual products</br>
        ii. they hate school</br>
        iii. they don't have the right information about menstrual products</br>
        `,
        answers: [
            "I only",
            "II only",
            "I and III",
            "I, II, III"
        ],
        correct: 2,
        info: "Period poverty is not just a lack of access to products. Providing girls and women with products is not enough; menstruation education is also crucial to solving the period poverty challenge."
    },
    {
        question: "<h1>All menstrual cycles last 28 days. True or false?</h1>",
        answers: [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        info: "A menstrual cycle can range anywhere from 21 days to 35 days depending on age and various health factors. The average menstrual cycle is 28 days, but a shorter or longer cycle doesnâ€™t necessarily mean your health is at risk."
    },
    {
        question: `
        <h1>Which are the possible effects of amenorrhea?</h1>
        i. infertility <br>
        ii. death<br>
        iii. none; I'd rather not have my period<br>
        iv. osteoporosis (bone density loss)<br>
        v. increased risk of heart and blood vessel disorders
        `,
        answers: [
            "I only",
            "I, II",
            "I, IV, V",
            "III",
            "I and IV"
        ],
        correct: 2,
        info: "Amenorrhea causes osteoporosis because estrogen levels drop and stay low. You may be delighted for your period to be gone, but if amenorrhea isn't treated, you will face the consequences long-term. Amenorrhea may also lead to infertility and pregnancy problems, and even an increased risk of heart and blood vessel disorders."
    },
    {
        question: "<h1>When proper products are not available, girls resort to using socks, dishrags, and newspapers. True or false?</h1>",
        answers: [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        correct: 0,
        info: "Lack of affordability and information have led many young women to use only one tampon per day or one pad for multiple days. When they lack access to products completely, women are often forced to use alternatives such as socks, dishrags, and newspapers during their periods."
    },
    {
        question: "<h1>In Kenya, it is reported that _ of females are unable to afford menstrual hygiene products.</h1>",
        answers: [
            "50%",
            "65%",
            "40%",
            "80%"
        ],
        correct: 1,
        info: "In Kenya, it is reported that 65% of females are unable to afford menstrual hygiene products. In addition, many rural schools lack private places for girls to change their menstrual products, causing numerous instances of gender-based violence around the non-private toilet facilities."
    }
]

